<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<service>
  <service_id>CAW-01</service_id>
  <title>Phasma3D Viewer</title>
  <service_type>3D Visualisation and Collaboration</service_type>
  <version/>
  <description>A collaborative 3D visualisation environment that resolves an RHDT project into its constituent entity instances (3D models, annotations, actor information) and renders them in a browser-based interface. Supports both client-side rendering via WebGL for mid-/high-tier devices and server-side remote rendering for large fragment collections and thin clients, enabling realistic illumination of results compatible with physical inspection. Includes 3D annotation tools (via ARTEMIS Annotation Services BEAS-01), geometry optimisation with Level of Detail (LOD) processing for 3D format conversion, and collaborative multi-user interaction. Server-side rendering is provided by AUEB-RC as an external Remote Rendering Server node.</description>
  <provided_by>
    <agent_type>Group</agent_type>
    <identifier/>
    <name>PHASMATIC</name>
    <email/>
    <homepage/>
  </provided_by>
  <access_points>
    <access_point>
      <url/>
      <endpoint_type>Web UI</endpoint_type>
      <endpoint_methods/>
      <notes>Browser-based WebGL 2 rendering interface. Compatible GPU with WebGL 2 support required on the client side.</notes>
    </access_point>
    <access_point>
      <url/>
      <endpoint_type>REST API</endpoint_type>
      <endpoint_methods/>
      <notes>Integration with ARTEMIS cloud data and services including authentication and data management.</notes>
    </access_point>
  </access_points>
  <intended_for>
    <audience>Heritage scientists and conservators engaged in collaborative 3D model inspection and annotation</audience>
    <audience>Expert users requiring remote, real-time collaborative work on 3D representations of heritage assets</audience>
    <audience>Users of RHDT pilots requiring 3D visualisation with multi-user access</audience>
  </intended_for>
  <used_for>
    <activity>
      <activity_label>operation_05 — Spatiotemporal Data Visualisation and VR/AR Experience: rendering the 3D models of the Japanese Tower ('as-is' and 'as-built') within the RHDT platform and overlaying environmental data layers</activity_label>
    </activity>
  </used_for>
  <used_physical_object_of_type>
    <object_type>Desktop or laptop computer with modern GPU supporting WebGL 2</object_type>
    <object_type>Server with NVIDIA RTX class GPU (min. 12GB VRAM, DLSS and OptiX denoiser support; indicative: RTX4090, RTX5090) for remote rendering — provided by AUEB-RC</object_type>
    <object_type>Server with min. 8 CPU cores (Intel i7/i9), min. 32GB RAM, min. 500GB storage for remote rendering</object_type>
  </used_physical_object_of_type>
  <has_functionality>
    <functionality>RHDT project resolution into entity instances (3D models, annotations, actors)</functionality>
    <functionality>Client-side WebGL 2 rendering of 3D models</functionality>
    <functionality>Server-side remote rendering for large fragment collections and thin clients</functionality>
    <functionality>Realistic visualisation and illumination of 3D results</functionality>
    <functionality>3D annotations (highlighting, sticky notes, comments) via ARTEMIS Annotation Services BEAS-01</functionality>
    <functionality>3D format conversion and Level of Detail (LOD) processing for geometry optimisation</functionality>
  </has_functionality>
  <composed_of>
    <sub_service>
      <sub_service_title>Annotation Service (BEAS-01 / BEDP-03)</sub_service_title>
    </sub_service>
    <sub_service>
      <sub_service_title>Remote Rendering Service (AUEB-RC external RRS node)</sub_service_title>
    </sub_service>
  </composed_of>
  <supported_language/>
  <media_type_consumed/>
  <media_type_produced/>
  <format_consumed>
    <format>model/gltf-binary</format>
    <format>application/json</format>
  </format_consumed>
  <format_produced>
    <format>application/json</format>
    <format>image/png</format>
  </format_produced>
  <support_contact/>
  <documentation/>
</service>
