<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<service>
  <service_id>BESS-07</service_id>
  <title>Predictive Indoor Climate AI Service</title>
  <service_type>Predictive Simulation / AI Forecasting</service_type>
  <version/>
  <description>An intelligent microservice providing backend infrastructure for forecasting future indoor climate conditions (temperature and relative humidity) of a specific heritage building or room. Operates in two stages: (1) Offline Model Training — a historical dataset correlating indoor IoCT time-series data with outdoor weather station data is used to train and validate a building-specific time-series forecasting model (e.g. LSTM networks, Gradient Boosting Machines or other regression models), producing a highly-tuned predictive model capturing the unique thermal inertia, air permeability and moisture buffering capacity of the asset; (2) Online Prediction (Inference) — once deployed, the service takes a future weather forecast (e.g. for the next 24–72 hours) as primary input, feeds it into the trained model and returns a time-series forecast of indoor climate for the same period. Called by the RHDT on a regular schedule via standardised REST endpoints. Training performed on a high-performance workstation or cloud instance with powerful CPU and preferably high-VRAM GPU. Inference deployed as a lightweight Python microservice (Flask or FastAPI) on a standard cloud CPU VM (8–16 GB RAM).</description>
  <provided_by>
    <agent_type>Group</agent_type>
    <identifier/>
    <name>Royal Institute for Cultural Heritage (KIK-IRPA)</name>
    <email/>
    <homepage/>
  </provided_by>
  <access_points>
    <access_point>
      <url/>
      <endpoint_type>REST API</endpoint_type>
      <endpoint_methods/>
      <notes>Python-based (Flask or FastAPI) or Node.js-based HTTP/HTTPS web server with JSON payload. Called by the RHDT on a regular schedule.</notes>
    </access_point>
  </access_points>
  <intended_for>
    <audience>Heritage building managers requiring proactive early-warning climate management</audience>
    <audience>Conservation scientists needing evidence-based forecasts of environmental risk for sensitive collections</audience>
    <audience>RHDT systems requiring predicted indoor climate data as input to the Risk Assessment Service</audience>
  </intended_for>
  <used_for>
    <activity>
      <activity_label>operation_02 — Predictive Indoor Climate Forecasting: generating 24-hour indoor temperature and RH forecasts for the Japanese Tower using real-time IoT data and external weather forecast data as inputs</activity_label>
    </activity>
    <activity>
      <activity_label>operation_04 — Risk Assessment and Alerting: providing short-term indoor climate forecasts as one of the three input data streams processed by the Risk Assessment Service</activity_label>
    </activity>
  </used_for>
  <used_physical_object_of_type>
    <object_type>High-performance workstation or cloud instance with powerful CPU and high-VRAM GPU (e.g. NVIDIA RTX series) for offline model training</object_type>
    <object_type>Standard cloud-based CPU virtual machine or container with 8–16 GB RAM for online inference deployment</object_type>
  </used_physical_object_of_type>
  <has_functionality>
    <functionality>Offline training of a building-specific time-series forecasting model (LSTM, Gradient Boosting Machines or other regression models)</functionality>
    <functionality>Online 24–72 hour indoor climate forecasting (temperature and RH)</functionality>
    <functionality>REST API-based forecast delivery to the RHDT on a regular schedule</functionality>
    <functionality>Support for early warning triggering and automated environmental control</functionality>
    <functionality>Virtual 'what-if' testing of climate control strategies without endangering the real asset</functionality>
  </has_functionality>
  <composed_of/>
  <supported_language/>
  <media_type_consumed/>
  <media_type_produced/>
  <format_consumed>
    <format>application/json</format>
    <format>text/csv</format>
  </format_consumed>
  <format_produced>
    <format>application/json</format>
    <format>text/csv</format>
  </format_produced>
  <support_contact/>
  <documentation/>
</service>
